无法摆脱工作的压力吗
Can't get the monkey off your back?
那就把它放进嘴里吧
Then put it in your mouth.
来杯猴子乐啤酒
with Monkeyshine Beer!
喝吧 猴子乐
Get it, monkey!
猴子乐 猴子乐
Monkey! Monkey!
猴子乐啤酒
Monkeyshine Beer.
因为外面是一片丛林
Because it's a jungle out there!
每次看到这个广告 我就很难过
That commercial always makes me so sad.
是呀 可是那个男的一打开啤酒
Yeah, but then the guy opens his beer
女人就对他投怀送抱
and those girls run at him.
所以结局看起来还不错
So everything seems to work out okay.
我的意思是 那只猴子让我想起了马塞尔
I meant because the monkey in it reminds me of Marcel.
我了解
I can see that.
因为他们都有一对棕色的大眼睛跟一个翘下巴
Because they both have those big brown eyes and y'know, the little pouty chin.
而且他们都是猴子
And the fact that they're both monkeys?
有时我会想知道 把他送走到底是对还是错
Sometimes I wonder if I did the right thing, you know, giving him away.
罗斯 你必须把他送走
Oh, Ross, you had to,
他能看见的东西都被他侵犯了
I mean, he was humping everything in sight.
害我的马里布芭比娃娃
I mean I have a Malibu Barbie
结婚再也不能穿白色的婚纱了
who will no longer be wearing white to her wedding.
还记得他会把你们的帽子借走
Remember when sometimes he'd borrow your hat,
等你要回来的时候 里面会有猴大便吗
and when you got it back, there'd be little monkey raisins in it?
他那样做很好玩
Yeah, well sure, when he did it, it was funny.
如果我对我老板那样做的话
When I did it to my boss's hat...
突然就变成了我的态度有问题
All of a sudden I had this big "attitude problem".
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧
《老友记》蓝光版 第02季 第12集
超级杯之后 The One After the Superbowl
调校制作：海盗美剧 寒 枫
字幕编辑：海盗美剧 小龟快快跑
嘿 嘿
Hey. Hey.
看看这个 你们猜猜我拿的是什么
Check it out! Guess what I got?
韵律
Rhythm?
不是 是我的第一封影迷来信
No. My first fan mail!
来看看
Check it out.
亲爱的雷莫瑞医生
"Dear Dr. Ramoray,
要知道 我爱你 我愿不惜一切得到你
Know that I love you and would do anything to have you."
天啊 你不神秘的仰慕者 艾瑞卡福特
My gosh! "Your not so secret admirer, Erika Ford."
等等
Oh, wait.
附注 请收下 我送的14根睫毛
"P.S. enclosed please find fourteen of my eyelashes."
在疯子的世界里 那就表示你结婚了
You know, in Crazy World, that means you're married.
这封信不是寄到"我们的日子"剧组
This wasn't addressed to "Days Of Our Lives".
收信地址是你家 上面没有邮票
This is, this came to your apartment. There's no stamp on it.
这女的来过咱们大楼
This woman was in our building.
我的天啊
Oh my God.
我竟然有自己的跟踪者了
I got my very own stalker!
嘿      嘿
Hey, guys.        Hey.
喔 你这是要去哪儿呀
Ooh, where are you off to, Traveling Jake?
在洛杉矶 有一个古生物学研讨会
Well, there's this paleontology conference in L.A.
所以我想我去 然后开车去动物园
So I figured I'd go and drive down to the zoo
给马塞尔一个惊喜
and surprise Marcel.
他会很惊喜的
You know I think he will be surprised.
直到发现自己是只猴子
Till he realizes he's a monkey,
根本不会有那种情绪
and you know, isn't capable of that emotion.
菲比 那个帅哥又来了
Oh, Phoebe, that really cute guy is here again.
噢 这样 各位
Oh, oh, Okay, so everyone,
假装我在跟你们讲故事
pretend like I'm telling you a story, okay?
而且是很好笑的故事
And it's really funny.
所以大家要笑 快
So everyone just laugh. Now!
我知道 我知道
I know, I know!
你好     嗨
Hello.         Hi.
我是罗伯杜南      你好 罗伯杜南
I'm Rob Donan.        Hi, Rob Donan.
我对音乐一窍不通
I don't know anything about music,
不过我觉得你很赞
but I think you're really really great.
喔 哇
Oh, wow!
我负责给市里的儿童图书馆安排演出
Anyway, I schedule performers for the children's libraries around the city.
我想知道 你有没有考虑过给孩子们唱歌
And I was just thinking, have you ever thought about playing your songs for kids?
我是很想有小孩
Oh. I would love to have kids...
听我唱我写给他们的歌
hear me play the songs that I will write for them.
晚餐吃什么
Hey, what do you wanna do for dinner?
我们可以自己煮
Well we could just stay in and cook for ourselves.
谁呀      我是艾瑞卡
Hello.        It's Erika.
天啊 是那个跟踪者
Oh my God. The stalker!
不用了 门没关
Never mind. It's open.
对 拿平底锅打她 好主意啊
Yes, hitting her with a frying pan is a good idea.
可是还得再有一个备用计划
We might wanna have a backup plan, though,
以防她不是卡通人物
just in case she isn't a cartoon.
我们快逃走吧
Let's get out of here!
偏挑这个时候不在家
The one time they're not home!
这样 这样 我们走就好了
Okay, okay, we'll just leave.
就算是碰到她
And when we pass her on the stairs,
她也认不出我 因为我们从没见过面
she won't know it's me because we've never met.
只有广播明星能这样摆脱跟踪者
That's how radio stars escape stalkers!
她来了
She's coming!
是我
It's me.
完了 我们就这样没命了
This is it. This is how we're gonna die.
准备好没      等等 等等
You ready?         Wait wait wait!
嗨
Hi.
艾瑞卡
Erika!
盖勒先生     是 你好
Mr. Geller?         Yes, hi!
你好 我是迪安利浦森 动物园园长
Hi. Dean Lipson, zoo administrator.
我听说你有个问题想问
I was told you had a question.
我找不到去年捐给动物园的猴子
Well, I, I can't seem to find the monkey I donated last year.
那只叫马塞尔的僧帽猴
He's a capuchin answers to the name Marcel?
恐怕我得告诉你坏消息
Ah.I'm afraid I have some bad news.
马塞尔已经过世了
Marcel has passed on.
天啊 怎么了
Oh my God. What happened?
他病了 病情越来越严重
Well, he got sick, and then he got sicker.
后来状况稍有好转
And then he got a little better.
可是最后他还是死了
But then he died.
我真是不敢相信
I can't believe this!
我很遗憾 盖勒先生
I'm sorry, Mr. GelIer.
但是 有句老话说得好
But you know,there's an old saying,
猴子难免一死
"Sometimes monkeys die."
虽然这不是什么至理名言 但是
It's not a great saying. But...
很适合用在今天这种状况
it certainly is fitting today.
你们应该打电话通知我的
Well, you know, someone should have called me.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我知道这无法让他复活 不过这是我们的一点心意
Look, I know this can't bring him back. But here it's just a gesture.
动物园代金券
Zoo dollars?
是啊 你可以观看四点钟的小鸟表演
Yes, and come see the bird show at four.
金刚鹦鹉戴帽子
The macaws wear hats.
如果你的猴子没死就更好了
Well, if a lot cuter if your monkey hasn't just died.
我知道
I know.
我简直不敢相信 乔伊竟然和跟踪者一起吃午餐
I can't believe Joey's having lunch with his stalker.
她长得什么样
What is she like?
记得"危情十日"里的凯西贝兹吗
Well, you remember Kathy Bates in Misery?
她跟她长的完全相反
Well, she looks the exact opposite of that.
那她不是疯子吗
And she's not crazy?
不是 她是个超级大疯子
Oh, no, no. She's a total wack job.
她认为乔伊就是德瑞克雷莫瑞医生
Yeah. She thinks that Joey is actually Dr. Drake Ramoray.
我的天啊
Oh my God!
这样他还跟她约会
Oh. And he's going out with her?
他不能这样
He cannot pursue this.
我们不能因为这个女人
Hey, just because this woman thinks
把电视里的乔伊 当作真的
she can actually see Joey through the magical box in her living room,
就不把她当人看啊
doesn't mean she's not a person.
难道她没有权利去爱 不能追求幸福吗
I mean, does she not deserve happiness? Does she not deserve love?
你们干嘛瞪我啊 是他自己要去跟疯子约会的
What are you looking at me for? He's the one who wants to boff the maniac.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
不好 我很紧张
No. I'm just, I'm nervous.
或许我可以想像他们只穿着内衣裤
So, you know, maybe if I just, if I picture them all in their underwear.
这样不太好
That's not a good idea.
上个表演者就是这样被开除的
That's kinda the reason the last guy got fired.
好吧
Yeah.
我只是习惯在大人面前表演
I'm just, I'm used to playing for grownups.
大人会边喝咖啡 边忙着自己的事情
You know, grownups drink their coffee and do their grownup thing, you know.
可是小孩子会认真听
And kids listen.
这个责任太重大了
This is a huge responsibility.
怎么了
What?
你要亲我吗
Are you gonna kiss me?
我是有这个打算
I was thinking about it.
好
Okay.
好耶 咱们来点儿音乐
Yeah, okay. Airighty. Let's play some tunes!
嗨 大家好 我是菲比
Hi, everybody. I'm Phoebe.
你好 菲比
Hi Phoebe!
好吧
Okay.
我要唱一首关于爷爷奶奶的歌 好吗
I'm gonna play some songs about grandparents, okay?
大家都喜欢奶奶
Now Grandma's a person who everyone likes.
奶奶会买给你火车 和闪亮的脚踏车
She bought you a train and a bright shiny bike.
可是她最近都没来吃晚饭
But lately she hasn't been coming to dinner.
你上次看到她时 她瘦了好多
And last time you saw her she looked so much thinner.
爸爸妈妈说 她搬去秘鲁了
Now your mom and your dad said she moved to Peru.
其实她已经死了 有天你也会死
But the truth is she died and someday you will too.
德瑞克 这真是太好了     对啊
Oh, Drake, isn't it amazing?         Yeah. it is.
怎么了
What?
我们现在很轻松地坐在这儿
Well, here we sit, devil may care.
但是不久之前 你还在重注西蒙的脊髓
And just a little while ago you were reattaching Simone's spinal cord.
对 那个手术很困难
Yeah, that was a tricky one.
其实那个手术花了十几个小时
In reality that operation takes like over ten hours,
但是他们只播了两分钟
but they only showed it for two minutes.
他们是谁
Who's "they"?
没什么啦
No one.
德瑞克 你好有才华喔 让我看看你的手
Oh, Drake, you are so talented. Let me see those hands.
这双手真是漂亮
Oh, these hands, these beautiful hands.
我真想把它们给吃了
Oh, I could just eat them.
可是我不会
But I won't.
很好 不然我的手表就会掉下来
Good. Otherwise my watch would fall off.
不 我是说真的
No, seriously.
这双手 这双创造奇迹的回春妙手
These hands, these miracle magical lifegiving hands.
只要能靠近它们 触摸它们 也许可以舔一下
Oh, just to be near them, touch them, maybe even lick one?
好吧 只舔一只喔
All right. Just one.
你还真厉害
You're good at that.
天啊 他噎到了
Oh, my God! Someone! He's choking!
这里有医生吗
Is anyone here a doctor?
有 这里有整个塞伦最优秀的医生
Oh, yes. Yes, the best doctor in all of Salem!
德瑞克雷莫瑞医生
Dr. Drake Ramoray!
15分钟后 咱们夜间馆见
Meet me in the nocturnal house in 15 minutes.
听着 我不喜欢跟男人做那种接触
Hey, look. I don't really enjoy being with other men that way.
你想要动物园代金券吗
But zoo dollars?
是关于你猴子的事情
It's about your monkey.
他还活着
It's alive.
我不明白 你为什么不帮那个人
I don't understand. Why didn't you help that man?
因为我是神经外科医生
Because, I'm a neurosurgeon.
而他的状况显然是
And that was clearly a case of...
食物阻塞症
"foodal chokage."
你知道
You know.
好吧 听着 我有事要跟你说
All right, look, I gotta tell you something...
不 不 不 不 你什么都不用说
No no no no.You don't have to tell me anything.
你不需要对我解释
You don't have to explain yourself to me. Oh!
我怎么可以质疑伟大的雷莫瑞医生     可是
Who am I to question the great Dr. Drake Ramoray?        But...
能接近你 我就很开心了      嘿
I should just be happy to be near you.        Hey, I...
嘿什么
"Hey" what?
没事 只是随口说声嘿
That's it. Just hey!
就像跳完舞之后也会说声嘿
Like at the end of a dance. Hey!
嘿
Hey.
等你们长大之后
There'll be times when you get older.
你会不惜跟喜欢的人上床
When you'll want to sleep with people.
只为博得对方的欢心 可是千万别这么做
Just to make them like you. But don't.
因为这是 你不该做的事情 一起来
'Cause that's another thing That you don't wanna do. Everybody!
你们不该这样做
That's another thing that you don't wanna do.
太棒了      非常有知识性
Excellent!         Very informative!
一点都没有不恰当
Not at all inappropriate!
谢谢大家的到来 后面有曲奇可以吃喔
Thank you for coming, everybody. There are cookies in the back.
你表演的真棒
That was great.
小孩子都很喜欢你
The kids loved you.
我超酷的吧
Yay! I rock!
你知道为什么吗 因为你跟他们说实话
And you know why? Because you told the truth.
从没有人会跟小孩说实话
And nobody ever tells kids the truth.
你真的太了不起了
You were incredible!
但是
But?
你怎么知道还有"但是"
How did you know there was a "but"?
我有感应
I sense these things.
不是"但是"就是"蛋糕"
It was either "but" or "butter".
我想有些父母
The thing is that I think, you know, some of the parents,
他们希望
they were kinda hoping that
你唱一些跟农场动物有关的歌
you'd play more songs about like barnyard animals.
没问题啊
I can do that.
真的吗     当然啦
Really?         Yeah.
这样就太好了      噢
Because that would be fantastic.         Oh.
怎么 你想亲我吗
What? You wanna kiss me?
正有这个打算
Thinking about it.
喔 蝙蝠
Ah the bat.
黑暗使者
Ambassador of darkness.
像长了翅膀的使者一般飞出洞中
Flitting out of his cave like a winged messenger.
看不见的幽灵
Sightless specter of the macabre.
老兄 我的猴子
Buddy, my monkey?
喔 对喔
Oh, yeah, right.
前几个月发生了一桩盗窃案 是监守自盗
There was a break in a few months back. Inside job.
你的猴子被偷走了
Your monkey was taken.
天啊 可是动物园跟我说我的猴子死了
Oh my God. The zoo told me that my monkey was dead.
动物园
The zoo!
动物园说的话你都相信吗
You believe everything the zoo tells you?
动物园就只跟我说了这一件事
That's the only thing the zoo's ever told me.
他们当然会这样说
Of course they're gonna say he's dead.
他们可不想坏事传千里
They don't want the bad publicity.
这是个大阴谋
It's all a great big cover-up.
你知道这件事 牵扯到多高层吗
Do you have any idea how high up this thing goes?
那个叫利浦森的人
That guy Lipson?
利浦森知道吗
Lipson knows?
利浦森知道啊
Lipson knows, huh?
你好 负鼠先生
Hello, Mr. Possum.
树上的谜团 爬上爬下的夜行者
Enigma of the trees, upsidedown denizen of the night.
无视于地心引力      老兄 我的猴子 我的猴子
Taunting gravity...        Buddy, my monkey. My monkey?
道上传闻
Word on the street.
我所说的"道上"
Well when I say "street",
是指动物园的人行道
I mean those little pretend streets they have here at the zoo.
我知道
Of course.
你的猴子找到了新工作
Your monkey found a new career
而且是在娱乐业 我只知道这么多
in the entertainment field. That's all I know.
这真是令人难以相信
This is unbelievable!
这样的消息值多少钱呢 朋友
So, what is this information worth to you, my friend?
你是要我贿赂你吗
Are you trying to get me to bribe you?
可能喔
Maybe.
但是你已经把一切都告诉我了
But you already told me everything.
你们看 他就是猴子乐啤酒广告里的那只猴子
Check it out. He actually is the Monkeyshine monkey.
你打算怎么办
Oh, wow. So, what are you gonna do?
打电话给啤酒公司 询问他的下落
Well, I guess I'm gonna call the beer company and try to find out where he is.
我的马不见的时候 我也是这么做的
That's what I did when I lost my Clydesdales.
大家好 我们又见面了
Okay, hi again!
你好 菲比
Hi Phoebe!
今天我们唱一些跟农场动物有关的歌
Today, we're gonna start with some songs about barnyard animals.
草地上的牛哞 哞 哞
Oh, the cow in the meadow goes "moo".
农夫打它们的头 并把它们的肉绞碎
Then the farmer hits him on the head and grinds him up.
汉堡包就是这么来的
And that's how we get hamburgers.
接下来是鸡
Now chickens.
只有你能救她 德瑞克
You're the only one who can save her, Drake!
拜托 我只是个医生 不是神仙
Damn it! I'm a doctor, I'm not God.
我的信仰就是这样被推翻了
Well there goes my whole belief system.
我是艾瑞卡
It's Erika.
天啊 快把电视关了
Oh my God, quick turn off the TV.
不要 等等 我想知道结果
No no no, wait, I wanna see what happens!
我帮助莱丝莉脱离昏迷 然后我们就亲热
I get Leslie out of the coma and then we make out.
怎么可能 你刚刚才亲了赛布丽娜
Well how can that be, you were just kissing Sabrina.
瑞秋 在那个世界里 乔伊是个神经外科医生
Rachel, it's a world where Joey is a neurosurgeon.
嘿 艾瑞卡 进来吧
Hey, Erika. Come in.
你怎么这么快就到家了 我刚还看到你在塞伦
How did you get here so fast? I just saw you in Salem.
是哦 他们用直升机送我回来的
Right, they choppered me in.
怎么啦
What's up?
你们在开派对啊
Oh, and I see you're having a little party too.
她在这里吗     谁啊
Is she here, huh. huh?         Who?
赛布丽娜 我知道你们的事了
Sabrina. I know about you two!
我看到你今天 在医生休息室里亲她
I saw you today kissing in the doctor's lounge.
事情不是你想的那样
It's not what you think. That was...
你还说我是你唯一的爱
You told me I was the only one!
好吧 够了
All right, look. That's it.
我们不该再继续交往了
I don't think we should see each other anymore, all right?
我知道 我应该早点告诉你的
Look, I know I  should have told you this a long time ago.
我不是德瑞克雷莫瑞
But I am not Drake Ramoray, okay?
我不是医生 我只是个演员
I'm not even a doctor. I'm an actor.
我只是假装自己是个医生而已
I just pretend to be a doctor.
我的天啊
Oh my God!
医院的人知道这件事吗
Do the people at the hospital know about this?
有人可以帮我一下吗
Somebody wanna help me out here?
我知道 我知道
Oh, I know! I know!
我在哪里
Where am I?
这里是大学附属医院
University Hospital.
你已经在这里昏迷了18年
The same place you've been for the last eighteen years.
你怎么会同时出现在两个地方
How can you be here and there?
因为那是电视剧
Because it's a television show.
德瑞克 你这话是什么意思
Drake, what are you getting at?
我不是德瑞克
I'm not Drake!
没错 他不是德瑞克 他是
That's right. He's not Drake. He's...
汉斯雷莫瑞 德瑞克的邪恶双胞胎兄弟
Hans Ramoray, Drake'sevil twin!
这是真的吗
Is this true?
是 是真的
Yes! Yes, it is true.
我之所以知道 是因为
And I know this because,
他假装自己是德瑞克 跟我上床
because he pretended to be Drake to sleep with me!
他还跟我说 他会跟我私奔
And then he told me he would run away with me.
可是他根本没有
And he didn't!
你还没把马桶座垫放下来 你这个混蛋
And you left the toilet seat up, you bastard!
这些都是真的吗
Is all this true?
是的
Yes.
恐怕是真的
I'm afraid it is.
我根本配不上你 艾瑞卡
You deserve much better than me, Erika.
你应该跟真正的德瑞克在一起
You deserve to be with the real Drake.
你爱的是他
He's the one you fell in love with.
去塞伦找他吧
Go to Salem. Find him!
他才是你的真命天子
He's the guy for you.
喔 汉斯
Oh, Hans.
汉斯 汉斯
Hans? Hans!
邪恶的双胞胎
You evil twin!
对 再见了 艾瑞卡
Right. Goodbye, Erika.
祝你在塞伦一切顺利
Good luck in Salem.
保重
Take care.
我永远不会忘记你的 汉斯
I'll never forget you, Hans.
好了 刚泼我水的人
All right. The people who threw the water!
我们是在帮你耶
Helping you out!
被炒了
Fired?
为什么
Why?
图书馆董事会接到很多来自家长的投诉
The library board has had a lot of complaints from parents
抱怨你歌词里的一些内容
about some of the stuff in your songs.
真不敢相信 你有没有跟董事会说
I cant believe it! Did you tell your board
孩子们想听实话
about how the kids want to hear the truth?
没有
No.
我明白了
I see.
或许 你可以唱一些一般的儿歌
Maybe if you just played some regular kiddie songs?
不要 你希望我变成什么样子 像那些
No. What do you want me to be? Like some
白痴的紫色大恐龙吗
stupid, big, like purple dinosaur?
我不是说 你要变成巴尼(紫色暴龙角色)
I'm not saying you have to be Barney.
巴尼是谁
Who's Barney?
我查到了马塞尔 并且得知
Well, I tracked down Marcel and get this.
他很健康也很快乐
He's healthy, he's happy.
而且他现在就在纽约
And he's right here in New York
拍 "极度恐慌2: 病毒侵袭曼哈顿"
filming "Outbreak 2. The Virus Takes Manhattan".
不会吧      我的天啊
You're kidding!        Oh my God!
真是太棒了      对啊
This is amazing.         I know.
我好不容易混进了电视圈
I finally get a part on TV.
这猴子都开始拍电影了
And the monkey's making movies.
瑞秋 我准备好了      好
Okay. Rachel, I'm ready.        Okay.
不好意思 请问这里有个会说实话的女歌手吗
Excuse me. Is this where the singing lady is who tells the truth?
应该就是我
Yeah, I guess that's me.
她在这里
She's here!
有时男人爱女人
Sometimes men love women.
有时男人爱男人
And sometimes men love men.
还有人是双性恋
And then there are bisexuals.
有些人却会说 他们只是在欺骗自己
Though some just say They're kidding themselves.
太兴奋了 我差不多一年没看到我的猴子了
This is so exciting. I haven't seen my monkey in almost a year.
怎么 你洗澡的时候都没往下看喔
What, you never look down in the shower?
我连说个"猴子等于命根子"的笑话都不可以吗
Oh, please. I'm not allowed to make one joke in the "monkeyis penis"genre?
请退后
Back up, please.
退后 快点 快点
Back up. Come on, come on.
不好意思 哪里可以找到那只猴子
Excuse me. Where can we find the monkey?
不好意思 今天的拍摄不开放
I'm sorry. It's a closed set.
你不了解 我是他的朋友
I'm sorry, you don't understand. I'm a friend of his.
我们以前住在一起
We used to live together.
对 我在波科诺斯也跟飞宝一起住过
Yeah. And I have a time share in the Poconos with Flipper.
罗斯 他在那里
Ross, there he is!
嘿 老兄
Hey! Hey, buddy!
马塞尔 马塞尔
Marcel! Marcel!
在丛林里 广大的丛林里
In the jungle, the mighty jungle,
今夜狮子睡着了
The lion sleeps tonight.
丛林里 广大的丛林里
In the jungle, the mighty jungle,
今夜狮子睡着了
The lion sleeps tonight.
他们不带你去看兽医
They won't take you to the vet
很显然 你不是他们最爱的宠物
You're obviously not their favorite pet.
臭猫 臭猫      臭猫 臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat.         Smelly cat, smelly cat.
这不是你的错      这不是你的错
It's not your fault.         It's not your fault.
不
No.
怎么了     抱歉
What?        I'm sorry.
有什么问题
What's wrong with that?
我想你应该选择一个 更男性化一点的调子比较好
I think you might wanna, like pick a more masculine note.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧